A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of Communications, Office Files of Carolee Iltis FA1870
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Office of Communications, Office Files of Carolee Iltis
1969-1996
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
Iltis, Carolee
FA1870
3.8 Cubic Feet 10 letter size boxes
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the office files Carolee Iltis created and maintained when she worked in various positions in the Ford Foundation's Office of Reports and Office of Communications. The files span across Iltis' full tenure at the Ford Foundation, including her positions as Assistant Administrative Officer and then Distribution Manager in the Office of Reports and later as Distribution Manager and then Manager for Dissemination and Administration in the Office of Communications. The Office of Reports was restructured into the Office of Communications.
The collection is comprised of two series. The first series, a set of work files, contains the bulk of the collection. Most of the work files document Iltis managing the distribution of individual publications. The second series contains a small run of Iltis' chronology files.
In managing the dissemination of the Ford Foundation's published works, Iltis ensured that the publications were sent to media representatives and other selected individuals and institutions, responded to requests for copies and reprints, handled copyright certification, and monitored and communicated about when the publications were out of print.
Common material formats in the collection include correspondence, publication copies, invoices, purchase orders, distribution notes, mailing lists, and drafts.
Arrangement
Collection is comprised of two series.
Original order was maintained as much as possible.
The collection arrangement is as follows:
Series 1. Work files, 1969-1996
Series 2. Chronology files, 1998-1999
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at the RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files, and officers' papers were transferred to and accessioned by the RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
This material was transferred to the RAC in three accessions between 2019 and 2022 and was ingested by the RAC as Accessions 2019:086, 2021:138, and 2022:034.
Ford Foundation; Documentary films -- Distribution
- Work files, 1969-1996; 1; 3.42 Cubic Feet 9 letter size boxes
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains work files Carolee Iltis created and maintained when she worked in the Ford Foundation's Office of Reports and Office of Communications. Almost all of the files in the series correspond to the titles of publications Iltis and her office disseminated. Job numbers are assigned to most of the files.
  Publications represented in the series are usually Ford Foundation original reports, reports reprinted by the Foundation from other publications, overviews of Foundation program activities, issues of the Ford Foundation Annual Report, issues of the Foundation newsletter, The Letter, and guides to films funded by the Foundation. Many of the publications are in the form of booklets.
  The files document the different processes and activities Iltis managed for distributing the publications including labeling, mailing, reprints, working with consultants, and copyright. Files often include distribution notes and slips describing the job.
  - Matters of Choice: A Ford Foundation Report on Alternative Schools, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Job No. 28-11 Measuring Social Innovation, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Job No. 27-33 Mediating Social Conflict, 1977-1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Job No. 79-84 Minorities and Housing: Are the Doors Really Open?, 1979-1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Job No. 79-65 Minding the Children: Ford Foundation Assistance to Child Care, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Job No. 81-20 Minorities and Mathematics: A Ford Foundation Staff Paper, 1981-1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Job No. 25-009 Minorities and the Media: A Ford Foundation Report, 1973-1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Job No. 28-36 Minority Admissions and Performance in Graduate Study, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Job No. 26-32 Minorities and Business: Ford Foundation Assistance 1965-1975, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Job No. 27-62 Mobilizing University Resources Against Hunger and Malnutrition: A Ford Foundation Reprint, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Job No. 81-27 Pedagogy for the Chiefs: A Ford Foundation Reprint, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Job No. 28-31 New Approaches to Conflict Resolution: A Ford Foundation Report, 1978-1986 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Job No. 23-12 International Programs of the Ford Foundation, 1972-1986 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Job No. 80-11 The New Delhi Seminar on Media, Government, and the Law, 1979-1986 (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
  - Job No. 26-55 Nine for Equality Upper Law: Civil Rights Legislation, 1976-1984 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Job No. 27-41 Patents and Collaboration Between the Private and Public Sectors: A Ford Foundation Reprint from the American Bar Association Journal, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Job No. 26-59 Paying for Schools and Colleges: A Ford Foundation Report, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Philanthropic Foundations in the United States: A Brief Description, 1969-1982 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Job No. 80-66 Philanthropy in Public Schools: One Foundation's Evolving Perspective, 1980-1985 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Job No. 28-14 Poor Rural Women: A Policy Perspective, 1977-1982 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Job No. 26-54 Poor, Rural, and Southern, 1976-1994 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Job No. 24-67 Population and Development: Is the Consensus Possible?, 1974-1983 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Job No. 27-38 Population Issues: From Obscurity to Worldwide Interest, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Job No. 80-59 The Preservation of the Cosmopolitan Research University in the United States: The Prospect for the 1980s, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Job No. 83-04 Program-Related Investments (PRI) photograph exhibit, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Job No. 22-17 The Public Interest Law Firm: New Voices for New Constituencies, 1973-1990 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Job No. 26-16 Public Interest Law: Five Years Later, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Job No. 80-05 Reform, Response and Renegotiation: Transitions in a School Change Project, 1979-1983 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Job No. 25-64 Relevance of Demographic Transition Theory for Developing Countries, 1969-1975 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Job No. 81-15 The Seminars on Media and Society 1974-1980: A Summary and Casebook, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Job No. 79-40 School Finance: The Rising Tide of Reform, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Job No. 81-06 Soviet-American Scholarly Exchange: Should Learning and Politics Mix?, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Job No. 25-53 The States and Private Foundations: A Ford Foundation Reprint, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Job No. 27-02 Theater Reawakening: A Report on Ford Foundation Assistance to American Drama, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Job No. 79-35 The Theater as Liturgy: A Ford Foundation Reprint, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Job No. 27-66 Title IX: Now What?, 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Job No. 26-58 Understanding Population, 1976-1984 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Job No. 83-22 The Ford Foundation and ... Urban Poverty?, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Job No. 24-69 Urban Studies and University - The Ford Foundation Experience, 1974-1980 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Job No. 26-17 The Value of College: A Non-Economist View, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Job No. 23-26 Venture Capital: A Ford Foundation Reprint from Black Enterprise, 1972-1990 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Job No. 26-39 Why Johnny Can't - The Problems of State School Financing, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Job No. 27-08 Widening the Mainstream of American Culture: A Ford Foundation Report on Ethnic Studies, 1976-1981 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Job No. 85-20 Women... A World Survey, 1984-1986 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Job No. 26-64 Working Against Hunger: Ford Foundation Grants in Agriculture, 1976-1979 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Job No. 25-68 Women at Mexico: Beyond Family Planning Acceptors, 1973-1976 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Job No. 80-68 "You're on Your Way", 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 48-49)
  - Job No. 90-25 Ford Foundation 1990 Annual Report - General, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 50-51)
  - Job No. 90-25 Ford Foundation 1990 Annual Report - Representatives, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Job No. 90-25 Ford Foundation 1990 Annual Report - Officers/Trustees, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Job No. 90-25 Ford Foundation 1990 Annual Report - Offprint, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Job No. 90-25 Ford Foundation 1990 Annual Report - Polling Returns, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Job No. 90-01 Ford Foundation 1989 Annual Report - General, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 56-57)
  - Job No. 90-01 Ford Foundation 1989 Annual Report - Representatives, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Job No. 90-01 Ford Foundation 1989 Annual Report - Officers/Trustees, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Job No. 90-01 Ford Foundation 1989 Annual Report - Offprint (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Job No. 90-04 Ford Foundation 1990 Fall/Winter Letter Vol. 21, No. 3, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Job No. 90-03 Ford Foundation 1990 Summer Letter Vol. 21, No. 2 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Job No. 90-02 Ford Foundation 1990 Spring Letter Vol. 21, No. 1, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Job No. 89-01 Ford Foundation 1988 Annual Report - General, 1988-1990 (Box 7, Folder 64-65)
  - Job No. 89-01 Ford Foundation 1988 Annual Report - Officers/Trustees, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Job No. 89-01 Ford Foundation 1988 Annual Report - Representatives, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - Job No. 89-01 Ford Foundation 1988 Annual Report - Offprint, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - Job No. 89-06 Ford Foundation 1989 February Letter Vol. 20, No. 1, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Changing Relations (CR): Newcomers and Established Residents in U.S. Communities, undated (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - Documentary Educational Resources Incorporated (DER), 1981-1993 (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - That Our Children Will Not Die, 1983-1991 (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Ford Foundation Films About Alternatives brochures, undated (Box 8, Folder 73-74)
  - Job No. 79-42 Ford Foundation Letter special edition for President George McBundy retirement - Not The Ford Foundation Letter, 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - Copyright information, 1985-1996 (Box 9, Folder 76-77)
  - Confronting the Nation's Urban Crisis: From Watts (1965) to South Central Los Angeles (1992) (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - Hispanic Experts Database, undated (Box 9, Folder 79)
  - George Washington University Center for Social Policy Studies publications, 1991-1994 (Box 9, Folder 80-81)
  - National Latino Immigration Survey, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 82)
  - Latino Research Center Development Program: A Preliminary Report, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 83)
- Chronology files, 1998-1999; 2; .38 Cubic Feet 1 letter size box
  This series contains a run of chronology files Carolee Iltis created and maintained when she served as Manager for Dissemination and Administration of the Ford Foundation's Office of Communications. The series only includes chronology files from the year 1998.
  The chronology files contain Iltis' correspondence. The correspondence documents Iltis' managing the distribution of the Foundation's published works and communications which included activities like labeling, mailing, copyright registration, and reprints. Some pieces also discuss the Office of Communication's budget and internal Foundation policies.
  - January-March 1998 Chron File, 1998-1999 (Box 10, Folder 84)
    File includes a couple pieces of correspondence from 1999.
  - July-September 1998 Chron File (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - April-June 1998 Chron File (Box 10, Folder 86)